Eswar Bharadwaj Gvs

Web Developer

Bengaluru
gvseswar1995@gmail.com
9550398091
eswargvs.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate **Web Developer** who places high value on **creativity** and **user-centered** design. Experienced in developing **responsive** and **user-friendly** applications for delivering **outstanding user experience**. Specialized in utilizing the **latest technologies** and improving the **performance** of the applications. Capable of **leading development teams** and communicating **complex technical ideas** to stakeholders who are not technically inclined.

EDUCATION

VIT UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Technology

Electronics and Communication Engineering—2014-2018

- Secured 8.45 CGPA in academics.
- Grew passion in coding and problem solving, that made me pick software engineering.

SKILLS

Languages-

Proficient->Javascript/Typescript, Intermediate-> Python, Beginner->Java

Web Technologies-

Proficient->Angular 2+, React JS, Node JS, HTML, CSS, Beginner->Flask, Webpack

Database-

Intermediate-> MongoDB, MySQL

Others-

Beginner-> Git, Docker, Rabbit MQ,

EXPERIENCE

AMADEUS SOFTWARE LABS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II – April 2022– PRESENT

- Worked on *Change Review* a change management tool, developed several key features in the tool, which granted users with a better user experience and many important functionalities. This increased the unique users from 300 to ~1000.
- Achieved a seamless transition of over 1800 users from an old tool to our tool by bridging the gaps.
- Integrated *ORCA* a job scheduling tool with Change Review using M*essaging Queues* and enabled users to reduce manual efforts in communicating between these two tools.
- Migrated all our tool's API from python 3.6 to 3.10
- Achieved a seamless cloud migration of our tool changereview.
- Worked on ticket templating solution which saved users around ~2500 hours
- Migrated the tool's code base into a mono repo to align with the policies.
- Dependency management using renovate

EMPROTO TECHNOLOGIES—ERGOS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - OCTOBER 2021 - April 2022

 Migrated an entire grainbank (provides storage and trading features for grains produced by farmers) website into an angular web application. Also developed additional features for creating filtered reports

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES—CITI

SYSTEM ENGINEER - JULY 2020 - OCTOBER 2021

 Monitoring and optimizing big data cluster performance, developing scripts for automating cluster optimizing techniques and generating reports on metrics of the cluster for a better handling of the cluster.

ASSISTANT SYSTEM ENGINEER - JULY 2018 - JULY 2020

- Migrated user modules and offer modules of an existing banking website into an angular application.
- Designed and developed a seating application for the managers which allows the manager to allot seats in respective office floors.
- Developed a drag and drop user interface on top of an open source library, which enables users to place web components and generate respective angular code for the user.

CRICKETADDA

FREELANCER - JULY 2020 - FEBRUARY 2020

Developed user interface for cricket score viewing web application based on ReactJS